Francisco Martinez. **Technical Writer**



Senior Technical Writer with over 23 years of experience and more than 16 years in writing and developing technical publications. Seeking work opportunities to further enhance my skills as a Technical Writer. 🚀 I'm also open to freelance writing and editing work.

✓ Accomplishments **Efficiency G**oals End result of docs

Contact

in LinkedIn GitHub Twitter

@ Send a mail

Experience

Tech Mahindra | TECHNICAL WRITER

Airbus L&M Programs Maintenance Docs TID Support

ijuly 2017 - Present | Seville, Spain (Hybrid)

Quest Global | TECHNICAL WRITER

Airbus MRTT Catalog & Structure Manual Responsible

october 2006 - june 2017 | Seville, Spain

Abengoa | Senior Project Designer

i october 2005 - october 2006 | Seville, Spain

Hidral Senior Project Designer

ijune 2005 - october 2005 | Seville, Spain

Auxiple Outsourcing | Airbus A380 Technical

Illustrator

december 2004 - june 2005 | Seville, Spain

Tecnocontrol | Senior Designer

iseptember 2004 - december 2004 | Seville, Spain

Dinotec Industrial Draftsman

ijune 2004 - september 2004 | Seville, Spain

Nilo - Aqualia Industrial Draftsman

october 2000 - june 2004 | Seville, Spain

Education

FPII Industrial Design (Certificate of Higher

Education)

Polytechnic Institute of Seville

iseptember 1998 - june 2001 | Seville, Spain

Languages

English: Full Professional Proficiency (B2)

Spanish: Fluent (Native)

Courses

IT Courses:

100% Responsive Web Design (HTML, CCS).

freeCodeCamp Certification.

70% Scientific Computing with Python. freeCodeCamp

Certification.

50% JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures.

freeCodeCamp Certification.

100% Automation Engineer Certification: Maven-

Jenkins-Selenium.TM Certificate.

100% Agile: Scrum Management. TM Certificate.

100% VBA and VBScript. TM Certificate.

TW and Design Courses:

100% Aircraft Systems Course: Electrical and Avionics.

100% Introduction to Aeronautical Systems: Hydraulic

and Pneumatic.

100% CAD Specialist.

100% Mechanical Design with CATIA V5.

100% Office Business Management (MS Word, Excel,

PowerPoint).

Languages Courses:

100% English Course Upper Intermediate (B2) Semi-

Intensive.

100% English Course Intermediate (B1-B2).

100% English Pre-Intermediate level (A2).

100% Simplified Technical English (ASD-STE100 v4).

Markup Languages	TW Tools	Technical Writing
XML	Arbortex	Wrinting
90%	90%	90%
HTML	Oxigen XML Editor	Translation
80%	50%	70%
CSS	MKDoks	Al tools
70%	80%	60%
Markdown	Jekyll	SEO
95%	40%	60%
reStructuredText	Docusaurus	
75%	30%	Specs
	Antora	\$1000D
Code	30%	90%
Python	Sphinx	DITA
60%	25%	60%
Javascript		Microsoft Writing Style Guide
45%	App & CMS	60%
SQL	Office	The Chicago Manual of Style
30%	80%	50%
JSON	Adobe	
60%	65%	Spoken languages
VB Script	Wordpress	Spanish
75%	75%	100%
Selenium IDE	Sensei LMS	English
45%	45%	70%

Main Interests

Reading: Enjoy reading fiction and non-fiction books on a wide range of topics, including science fiction, history, and technology.

Sports: Regularly participate in hiking and cycling to maintain physical fitness and mental well-being.

Travel: Passionate about exploring different cultures and have traveled to various countries to experience diverse lifestyles and broaden my horizons.

Volunteer Work: Actively involved in non-profit organizations.